Mohamed Sharukh

email: sharukhsm@gmail.com Address: Coimbatore, Tamilnadu, India



Portfolio



G Github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a web developer who loves to build experiences that help others do what they couldn't do before.

I love using technology to enable others and feel most fulfilled when using my skills to do. I'm a strong advocate for diversity and inclusion in the tech industry.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Sri Krishna College Of Engineering And Technology | 2015 - 2019

Coimbatore

B.E. Electronics And Communication Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React JS | JavaScript
- Node | Express
- HTML | CSS
- Bootstrap
- Java
- SQL | MongoDB
- GIT I Github

PROJECTS

- Fall detection system with heart rate monitoring using pic Microcontroller. It is used to detect fall for the elderly and patients.
- Home Automation using Arduino and WiFi module ESP8266. It is the prototype for a home automation system using WiFi technology.

in LinkedIn Profile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Infosys

Systems Engineer - React JS Developer July 2021 - Present

- · The client is a Healthcare company. Molina is a web application used by the client's subscribers and dependents. This application helps users to track their health records, spending, wellness, bills, plans, etc.
- Developed a High-performance customer-facing Healthcare application using ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap in an Agile environment. Exclusively used React-Hooks to handle application life cycle processes.

Cognizant

Programmer Analyst

November 2019 - February 2021

- · During training, I created a web project called Interview scheduling management using HTML/CSS, Javascript, Java and spring boot framework. It is the process of sprinting between hiring managers, busy candidates and the right interviewers to make interviews happen.
- Contributed significantly to the migration of legacy systems to React web applications, ensuring that all business-critical functions were preserved.
- · Assisting team members with technical challenges.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Web Development Bootcamp Completed a 55 hours immersive web development course on Udemy.
- Attended workshop on IBM cognitive cloud at National Institute of Technology, Tiruchirappalli.

CO - CURRICULAR AND EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Presented a paper titled Blue Brain in the IEEE sponsored international conference - ICRAET.
- I was a part of the company's annual camps, also known as "Cognizant outreach," in which we invited underprivileged children from our community to visit the offices.